Every family has its demons.
Dark Shadows is a comedy, fantasy film directed by Tim Burton.
Vampire Barnabas Collins is inadvertently freed from his tomb
and emerges into the very changed world of 1972.
He returns to Collinwood Manor to find that his once-grand
estate and family have fallen into ruin.
Barnabas Collins, played by Johnny Depp.
Elizabeth Collins Stoddard, played by Michelle Pfeiffer.
Angelique Bouchard, played by Eva Green.
Dr. Julia Hoffman, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Carolyn Stoddard, played by Chloë Grace Moretz.
Victoria Winters / Josette DuPres, played by Bella Heathcote.
Dark Shadows is a 2012 Gothic dark fantasy comedy horror film based
on the Gothic television soap opera of the same name.
Directed by Tim Burton, the film stars Johnny Depp alongside Michelle Pfeiffer, Eva Green, Jackie Earle Haley,
Jonny Lee Miller, Chloë Grace Moretz, Helena Bonham Carter, and Bella Heathcote in a dual role.
Christopher Lee has a small role in the film, marking his 200th film
appearance and his fifth and final collaboration with Burton.
Jonathan Frid, star of the original Dark Shadows series, makes a cameo
appearance, and died shortly before the film was released.
One of the film's producers, Richard D.
Zanuck, died two months after its release.
The film had a limited release on May 10, 2012, and was
officially released the following day in North America.
It performed poorly at the United States box
office, but did well in foreign markets.
Reviews for the film were mixed; critics praised its visual style and consistent humor,
but felt it lacked a focused or substantial plot and developed characters.
The film explores themes of witch, vampire,
imprisonment, curse, fish out of water.
The tone is lighthearted.